{"tossups": [{"question": "This man, as Public Safety Director of Cleveland, controversially ordered the burning of its shanty towns in response to the Cleveland Torso Murderer. This man co-wrote a memoir with Oscar Farley which was named for a term coined by Charles Schwarz. George Johnson appointed this man to head a group dedicated to prosecuting criminals under the Volstead Act. This man\u2019s inability to be bribed by the Chicago Outfit led him and his men to be labeled the \u201cUntouchables.\u201d For the point, name this Prohibition-era crime fighter who helped bring down Al Capone.", "answer": "Eliot<b> Ness</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "One woman during this period was strangled after her infant son, nicknamed \u201coffspring of the thief,\u201dwas hanged. Jacob De La Gardie helped defeat the Rebel of Tushino during this period, but defected when Dmitri Shuisky failed to lift the Siege of Smolensk after being defeated by winged hussars at the Battle of Klushino. This period began after Feodor the Bellringer was briefly succeeded by Boris Gudonov. At least four pretenders to the throne named False Dmitris appeared during, for the point, what tumultuous era which ended with the accession of Michael Romanov?", "answer": "<b> Time of Troubles</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "This is the<em> smallest</em> religion by devotees whose idols can be found at the Ellora Caves. This religion\u2019s abandoned temples include a complex found at Nagarparkar in southern Pakistan. This religion\u2019s holiday of Kshamavani is a day of forgiveness that occurs at the end of the<em> Paryushana</em>, which lasts 8 or 10 days depending on if one follows the Swetambara or Digambara sect. This religion venerates a set of 24 \u201cford-makers\u201d called<em> tirthankaras</em>. Mahavira led a revival of, for the point, what Indian religion that espouses<em> ahimsa</em>, or non-violence?", "answer": "<b> Jain</b>ism", "metadata": "Religion - Religion"}, {}, {"question": "One of these places was established at Bobbio by a man who was exiled by Theudoric II of Austrasia from another of these places at Luxueil. Iona was established by Colomba at the beginning of the Hiberno-Scottish Mission to establish these places, one of which produced a namesake gospel book honoring Saint Cuthbert in the Insular art style; a Viking raid on that one of these places at Lindesfarne ended the cultural dominance of these places. Illuminated manuscripts like the Book of Kells were created in, for the point, what religious complexes established by Celtic Christian monks?", "answer": "Irish-founded<b> monasteries</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "The death of Toghrul in the hands of the Naiman army ended the autonomy of the Keraites, an early group of these people. One work about these people opens with the kidnapping of one figure\u2019s mother named Hoelun and then chronicles that figure\u2019s familial feud with his brother Jamukha. Leaders of these people were protected by the<em> kheshig</em> royal guards, whose creation was described in a secret history of these people. The<em> yassa</em> law code provided a legal framework for, for the point, what group of nomadic peoples unified by Genghis Khan?", "answer": "<b> Mongol</b>s or<b> Mongolian</b>s", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "One champion of this cause linked it with religion in his essay<em> Faith and the Future</em> and rejected the idea of the rights of man, claiming that rights had to be worked for and won in an essay which advocated this cause,<em> The Duties of Man</em>. Early supporters of this cause included \u201ccharcoal burners,\u201d members of the Carbonari secret society. Pope Pius IX refused to support this cause, declaring himself the prisoner of Count Cavour and Victor Emmanuel II. For the point, name this cause advocated by Guiseppe Mazinni which created a new country with its capital in Rome.", "answer": "<b> Italian Unification</b> (accept Il<b> Risorgimento</b>) Page 2", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "A member of this family proposed the resolution officially declaring the United States\u2019 independence to the Second Continental Congress. George Washington gave command of federal troops in the Whiskey Rebellion to a member of this family. An estate owned by this family was transformed into the Arlington National Cemetery. A general from this family was forced to abandon Richmond in 1865 and days later surrendered to Ulysses S. Grant at Appomattox Court House. For the point, name this Southern dynasty that included Virginians \u201cLight Horse\u201d Harry and Robert Edward.", "answer": "<b> Lee</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "John Howard\u2019s conclusions in his work<em> The State of [these institutions]</em> were opposed by Elizabeth Fry, who worked to improve this institutions after visiting one at Newgate. Michel Foucault argued that these institutions evolved from public displays of torture as a more scientific way to regulate power and violence.<em> Discipline and Punish</em> is subtitled \u201cthe birth of\u201d this institution, one of which was designed so that the constant threat of surveillance from a single watchman enforced discipline. The Panopticon is an example of, for the point, what institution where criminals are locked up?", "answer": "<b> prison</b> (accept<b> penitentiary</b> or<b> jail</b>)", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Sociology"}, {"question": "Henry Fourdrinier invented a namesake machine to industrialize making this product. Two prisoners captured at the Battle of Talas were brought back to Samarkand to teach the creation of this product to the Islamic world. After watching wasps, Cai Lun was inspired to make this product, which used rags, hemp and mulberry. Song dynasty Jiaozhi and Huizhi money was the first to be made of this material. Unlike parchment or papyrus, this material is now usually made of wood pulp. For the point, name this product on which books can be printed.", "answer": "<b> Paper</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "The moustache of a pilot involved in this conflict has recently become a fashion trend in his home country. The Balakot airstrike occurred during this conflict in retaliation against the 2019 Pulwama attack. Fighting in this conflict frequently occurred on the Siachen glacier and the Kargil War was a part of this conflict. The Simla Agreement established the Line of Control which separates two sides in this conflict. For the point, name this long running territorial conflict over a mountainous former Princely State between India and Pakistan.", "answer": "<b> Kashmir</b> Conflict (Prompt on India-Pakistan Conflict)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "In a 2007 film, Julia Roberts played Joanne Herring opposite this man, who played a US Congressman who strongly supported Operation Cyclone funding the mujahideen in Afghanistan. This star of<em> Charlie</em> <em>Wilson\u2019s War</em>, who also played Jim Lovell in<em> Apollo 13</em>, won consecutive Best Actor Oscars in 1993 and 1994 for<em> Philadelphia</em> and a film in which he somehow personally experiences much of 20th century American history. For the point, name this star of<em> Saving Private Ryan</em> and<em> Forrest Gump</em>.", "answer": "Tom<b> Hanks</b>", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "In a 1961 massacre orchestrated by Maurice Papon, over 40 people from this country were driven off the Saint-Michel Bridge and drowned. One organization supporting continued colonial presence in this modern-day country used<em> stroungas</em> in terrorist bombings; that organization was the Secret Army Organization, or OAS. Technically considered as part of the<em> metropole</em>, this country was settled by 1 million Europeans known as<em> pieds-noirs</em>. This country\u2019s FLN won its independence in the Evian Accords. For the point, name this North African former French colony.", "answer": "<b> Algeria</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "A Maoist insurgency led by this country\u2019s two different Communist parties resulted in a period of dramatic change called Krambhanga after the abolition of this country\u2019s monarchy in 2006. This country\u2019s Crown Prince Dipendra killed several of his family members and himself in 2002. This country supplies gurkha soldiers to the British Army, and this country\u2019s Sherpa people are part of its Buddhist minority. For the point, name this country on the Indian subcontinent where almost 9,000 people died in a 2015 earthquake in its capital of Kathmandu.", "answer": "<b> Nepal</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "A temple dedicated to Al-Uzza in this city is named for its Corinthian column capitals, which feature winged lions. This city\u2019s Wadi Musa was said to be the location where Moses made water spring up from rock. The most famous building in this city was constructed by King Aretas IV and can be accessed through a narrow gorge. This city\u2019s largest monument is dedicated to the deified king Obodas I and is El Deir, or the Monastery. The Siq leads to the Khazneh Treasury carved into red sandstone cliff in, for the point, what capital of Nabatea that is located in Jordan?", "answer": "<b> Petra</b> (accept<b> Raqmu</b>) Page 4", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {"question": "Chemical weapons were used in this country after Tito Minniti was allegedly tortured and mutilated by troops here. A leader of this country decried \u201cdeath-dealing rain\u201d in a speech opposed by Nicolae Titulescu. Emilio De Bono was replaced as military commander of one force invading this country by Pietro Badoglio. A leader of this country declared \u201cit is us today, it will be you tomorrow\u201d in a 1936 speech to the League of Nations. For the point, name this country, where Italian troops invaded the homeland of Haile Selassie.", "answer": "<b> Ethiopia</b>n Empire (prompt on \u201cAbyssinia\u201d)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "A symphony by this composer imitates an invention of his friend Johann Maelzel, the metronome. Right after the JFK assassination, the Boston Symphony Orchestra stopped their program to play the second movement of this composer\u2019s third symphony, a C-minor funeral march. During the Second World War, a piece by this composer was used as the Allied sign for victory. That work by this composer begins with a motif that has been compared to fate knocking at the door. The European Union\u2019s anthem uses, for the point, which composer\u2019s setting of the poem \u201cOde to Joy\u201d?", "answer": "Ludwig van<b> Beethoven</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {"question": "During a 1919 strike in this industry, the US military seized Gary, Indiana and declared martial law. Secretary of Commerce Charles Sawyer was sued by a Youngstown-based company due to the President\u2019s response to a strike in this industry. In 1952, Harry Truman nationalized this industry hours before a strike was set to begin. Pinkerton agents attempted to break up a strike in this industry on the orders of Henry Clay Frick. The Homestead Strike was started by workers in, for the point, what industry historically based out of Pittsburgh?", "answer": "<b> steel</b> (prompt on metallurgy industry)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This attorney argued that optional jury duty for women was discriminatory in<em> Duren v. Missouri</em>. While a professor at Rutgers, this attorney argued that section 402(g) of the Social Security Act discriminated against a male widower in<em> Weinberger v. Wiesenfeld</em>. This co-founder of the ACLU\u2019s Women\u2019s Rights Project struck down VMI\u2019s male-only admission policy as part of her longtime advocacy for women\u2019s rights. For the point, name this liberal Associate Justice, only the 2nd woman, after Sandra Day O\u2019Connor, to serve on the Supreme Court.", "answer": "Ruth Bader<b> Ginsburg</b> (accept<b> RBG</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "One work by this artist depicts a one-eyed leader taking a word-oath during the Batavian Rebellion and is titled<em> The Conspiracy of Claudius Civilis</em>. This artist depicted himself holding a beer with his wife Saskia on his lap in<em> The Return of the Prodigal Son in the Tavern</em>. A turbaned king is horrified by a disembodied hand writing Hebrew on the wall in one work by this artist,<em> Belshazzar\u2019s Feast</em>. Another work by this painter is held in the Rijkmuseum and depicts the militia company of Franz Banning Cocq. For the point, name this Dutch painter of<em> The Night Watch</em>.", "answer": "<b> Rembrandt</b> van Rijn", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {}, {}, {"question": "The disappearance of Sneha Anne Philip was controversially added to the death toll of this event, whose survivors were aided by the James Zadroga Act. Barbara Lee was the only representative to vote against the AUMF legislation passed in the wake of this event. Cantor Fitzgerald and Marsh & McLennan suffered over 800 deaths in this event. Richard Drew\u2019s<em> The Falling Man</em> depicts this event, which followed a 1993 bombing attempt on its main target. For the point, name this al-Qaeda led attack where planes crashed into the Pentagon and the World Trade Center in 2001.", "answer": "<b> September 11</b> attacks (or<b> 9/11</b> attacks)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "One man who held this position was killed in the 10.26 incident by the director of the KCIA. That man\u2019s daughter later became the first woman to hold this position until she was impeached in 2016. One man who gained this position in a coup carried out the Gwangju massacre and was named Chun Doo-Hwan. The first man to hold this position led his country through a conflict with a northern neighbor and was named Syngman Rhee. Park Chung Hee and Park Geun-Hye held, for the point, what position whose holders live in the Blue House in Seoul?", "answer": "<b> President of South Korea</b> (Accept<b> President of the Republic of Korea</b>, accept <b>Daehan Minguk Daetongnyeong</b>) (35) This man wrote \u201cwe are not at fault for slaying\u201d the title people in his anti-Semitic pamphlet \u201cThe Jews and their Lies.\u201d This man attempted to refute claims that his teachings were causing unrest by writing \u201cAgainst the Murderous, Thieving Hordes of Peasants.\u201d This man dismissed good works by insisting upon the doctrine of<em> sola fide</em> [fee-day] and debated the Eucharist at the Marburg Colloquy with Ulrich Zwingli. Anger at Johannes Tetzel\u2019s selling of indulgences prompted, for the point, what man to nail his 95 Theses to a church in Wittenberg? ANSWER: Martin<b> Luther</b> Page 7", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "John Wesley Dobbs led this city\u2019s Sweet Auburn neighborhood, which was devastated by a 1917 fire in its Old Fourth Ward. Joseph Terrell ended this city\u2019s namesake 1906 race riot, after which M. Hoke Smith disenfranchised this city\u2019s black voters. Eric Rudolph detonated a pipe bomb during this city\u2019s 1996 Summer Olympics. A Confederate monument outside this city is the largest bas-relief in the world and was the site of the founding of the 2nd KKK. Stone Mountain is in a suburb of, for the point, what capital and largest city of Georgia.", "answer": "<b> Atlanta</b> Page 8", "metadata": "History - American History"}], "bonuses": []}